Hello friends, my name is Abhishek Gal and
welcome to my channel Invest Insurance. Friends,
ICC Lord General Insurance has launched a new health
insurance product through which
you can take your health insurance requirement to the
next level. Yes
friends, I am talking
about the Elevate product, in which the company has
given you such features which you
search for in every different health insurance plan
but you are not able to find it. In this you
get unlimited Shamsher experience.
In this you get entry limit up to 125 years.
In this you get
unlimited no claim bonus. In this you get
unlimited reston. There are many such
features which are given in it, which you
can add to your policy and make it a fully featured policy. So let's move ahead
and understand this product in detail.
Before moving ahead in the video,
friends, if you have come to our channel for the first time, then
please subscribe to the channel so that
all of you keep getting such great information.
And at the same time, if you like the video, then
like and share it. Your every like
motivates us. Such a great  To
make information videos, let's cover the
product in detail. First of all, let's talk about the
sum assured. In this product, the minimum
sum assured is Rs 5 lakh and there is no limit on the maximum sum
assured. Friends, the
option of unlimited coverage is being given.
If I talk about the entry age, then the
minimum entry age is 18 years and the maximum
entry age is 125 years. Friends, there was a time when the
company used to provide coverage for 99 years as well,
but now that barrier of 100 years has been
removed. Now you are being given coverage up to 125 years as well.
If I
talk about the dependent child maximum age limit, then here an average of up to 30 years is being given.
As far as other policies are concerned, in
them a maximum of 25
years is given. There are only a few
policies in which you get coverage of 30 years.
If I talk about room rent, then it provides a
single private AC room. You are
not being given a higher category room.
If I  If I talk about pre and post hospital
expenses, that is, the
expenses before hospitalization and after discharge, then in case
of pre hospitalization, the company is giving you coverage of up to 90 days
and in case of post
hospital expenses, you are being given coverage of 180 days.
Along with this, the company is
providing you a cool bonus, that is, as
soon as you renew the policy, the
company increases your sum insured by 20%,
which increases up to a maximum of 100%
and the best thing is that even
if you get a claim tomorrow, it does
not get reduced, that is, your
policy doubles in 5 years. If I
talk about restore benefit, then here the
company is providing you unlimited registration. The same
person gets
registration for the same illness but
with the gap of 45 days. Along with this, the company is providing you coverage of road
ambulance, day care treatment, organ donor
modern treatment, domiciliary hospitalization,
biological surgery etc.
Next is wellness services. So, if you are
maintaining a healthy lifestyle, then the
company is providing a discount of up to 30% on your renewal premium.
In this, basically you have to earn some points
through their application, which the
company tracks and accordingly
you get a discount on the renewal premium.
Next is modern and advanced
treatment. Today, many
surgeries have become robotic and are being done
through knife surgery. So, the
company is providing coverage for all these, that too up
to the sum insured. Next is surrogacy and
U-donor. If any couple is facing a pregnancy-
related problem and they
want to go for some alternative treatment
like surrogacy or U-donor cover, then the
company is providing coverage for that as well,
with a coverage of up to ₹ lakh. Next is
Ayu treatment i.e. Ayurveda, Yuga,
Unani, Siddha, Homeopathy. So,
if someone
wants to go for all these types of treatments instead of allopathy, then the
company will provide coverage for that as well.
Up to sum insured is being insured. Now let's talk about the
optional benefits which are available in this product. The
first option benefit is
Ifit Care. Friends, in this the company
says that if you choose this option tomorrow, if
you have a policy of Rs 5 lakh or Rs 10 lakh
and due to any critical
illness you get a huge claim, then the
company settles your entire claim
in one go. For example, if
you have a policy of Rs 5 lakh and in the first or
second year you get a huge claim of Rs
40 lakh or Rs 50 lakh, if you have chosen this option, then the
company settles your entire claim. The
only condition of the company is
that you can select it only once in the entire policy years
and
you are being given the option to select this option only in the first 2 years,
after that
you cannot select this option. Next
is Power Booster, apart from normal
[ __ ] a bonus. Here the company, if you choose this
option  If you choose it, then it gives 100% cumulative
bonus, that too for unlimited times, that is,
if you have a policy of Rs 10 lakh and you are
continuing the policy every year, then the
company is increasing your sum insured by 100% every year. A
policy of Rs 10 lakh will become Rs 20
lakh, a policy of Rs 20 lakh becomes Rs 30 lakh,
so this will continue continuously. The
only condition of the company here is
that you do not get this option in unlimited cover.
Next is Jump Start, so
this is trending in today's date, where
if a person has a pre-existing
disease like asthma, BP,
sugar, cholesterol as well as obesity
and if the person
wants instant cover for it, then if he chooses this option, then
he gets its coverage only after 30 days. The
condition of the company is that
all these diseases should be at least 1 year old.
Next is Claim Protector,
so non-medical items like  Gloves, masks,
PP kits, which normally
cost 4 to 5 percent of your hospital bill, so if you
select this option, then you are
also being given coverage for that up to sum
insured. Next is inflation
protector. If you choose this option, then
every year the
company increases your sum insured according to the inflation rate.
Next is domestic air ambulance.
In this option, the company is
also providing you the services of up to sum insured air ambulance.
Next is dependent accommodation
benefit. So, if tomorrow the insured person gets
hospitalized and whoever stays with him, then the
company bears his expenses here, which is Rs.
000 per day, which is a maximum of
10 days.
Next is room modification. Here,
by default in the policy, you
get a single private TC room, but if you
choose this option, then the company is giving you two
options. If you want, you
can upgrade your room or downgrade it.  If
you upgrade, your
premium increases slightly. However,
if you downgrade your room, i.e.,
move to a shared room, then your
premium gets a discount of a certain percentage.
Next is Compassionate Visit.
If you are in a city other than your own
and get hospitalized there due to some emergency
for more than five
days, then your immediate family member is
provided airfare to come to you.
Here the company is providing coverage of up to ₹2000000 for that as well.
Next is
Nursing at Home. Friends, many times it happens that
after leaving the hospital, we have
some treatment or some such things
due to which we need a nurse at home as well, then the
company provides coverage for that as well.
So here, if you
choose this option, then
coverage of ₹2000000 to ₹1 lakh is being given.
Next is Newborn Baby Coverage. So, if you are
taking maternity benefit, then the company is
also providing you Newborn Baby Coverage in
which basically the child is covered.
You get coverage for up to 90 days and a maximum of 2x
the maternity cost.
Next is vaccination for newborn baby.
Apart from the normal
maternity limit, the company is providing coverage of % of sum assured
or maximum ₹1000000.
Next is durable
medical equipment cover. Friends, many times it happens
that due to some other illness or
accidental injury, the doctor suggests us durable
medical equipment like wheel chairs, walkers,
all these types of medical equipment
which are
not normally covered in health insurance. If you choose this option, then the
company is providing coverage of up to ₹1 lakh for the
same. Next
is conventions benefit. If the insured
person is hospitalized for more than 10 days, then the
company is providing a separate benefit of ₹2000000
as a cash
benefit.  Next is health checkup. The company gives
you 5 percent off sum assured every year or a
maximum of ₹5000000 and the insured should be
below 65 years of age. Next is
tele-consultation. If you choose this option,
you can chat with the company unlimitedly
for your routine health issues.
Next is the option to reduce your maternity
waiting period. If you use this option,
your maternity waiting
period, which is normally
2 years in this product, gets reduced from 2 years to 1 year.
Next is voluntary
copayment. If you choose this option, the
company provides a discount on your premium. However,
whatever your voluntary copayment,
here the company has given the option of voluntary copayment ranging from 10 percent to 50 percent.
If you choose any of these options,
you will have to pay that much amount. The
rest is paid by the health insurance company
whenever you have a claim in the future.  For
example, if you have taken a co-payment of Rs. 10 per
and your bill comes to Rs. 1 lakh, then
you will have to pay Rs. 10,000 from your pocket. The
rest is provided by the health insurance company.
Next is Network Advantage. If you
choose this option, then the company
provides a discount of Rs. 10 on your premium. But the condition of the company is
that whenever you are hospitalized,
you must be admitted in their preferred network hospital.
If you are admitted
in a non-network or non-preferred hospital
and whatever your bill is, then
you have to pay a co-payment of Rs. 20.
Next is personal accident cover. So, if the
insured person dies due to an accident, then
whatever sum is insured is
given to his nominee. Here the maximum
limit of sum insured is Rs.
50 lakh and the maximum entry age is
65 years. Next is critical illness cover. So,
if you choose this option, then the company
's Rs. 20  If you suffer from any of the critical illnesses, the
company provides you with a
lump sum benefit, which you
can use for that illness. The company's
condition is that you get a maximum
coverage of Rs 50 lakh.
If any insured person suffers from any of these
critical illnesses, his age should be
below 50 years at the time of first occurrence
of that particular critical illness. So
friends, in this way we have
covered all the option benefits of the product. Now let's talk about the
waiting period. So friends, here the
company has an initial
waiting period of 30 days for all diseases except
for accidental claims. Next is the waiting
period for critical illness. So, here the company has
given a waiting period of 90 days for critical illness. If I talk about specified
illness or slow-growing illness, the waiting
period is for such diseases which
develop slowly in our body like kidney stone,
hernia.  For piles, cataracts, etc., the
company has given a waiting period of 2 years for all these.
If I talk about the waiting period for pre-existing diseases like
BP, sugar, etc. before buying a policy, then
here the
company has given a waiting period of 3 years. Along with this, the
company has
also given a waiting period of 2 years for bariatric surgery. There is
also a waiting period of 0 years for maternity coverage. Along with this, the
company has given a waiting period of 90 days
for any hospitalization due to
hypertension, diabetes, and any cardiac issue.
Now let's talk about network hospitals.
ICC Lombard has almost 7 to 8000
network hospitals, so almost all the
big hospitals are in its network list. In
case due to some other emergency, if you get
your treatment done in a non-network hospital, then
submit the bill report to the company, the company will pay you your money.
And if you also want cashless, then today there
is a facility of cashless anywhere,
for which you have to contact the company.  You will have to inform 48 hours in advance
to get the cashless
facility in case due to some other emergency.
If you get admitted, then within
48 hours of admission, if you inform the company, then the
company talks to the hospital and
tries to make your claim cashless.
So friends, in this way we have
covered all the things of the product. Now let's talk about the
premium, here the company has
divided the premium into four zones. If you
look at the screen here, then it has been divided
into four categories - Zone A, Zone B, Zone C and Zone D.
Your
premium is charged according to the category you belong to. Even if you go to a higher zone, that is,
if you bill in Zone C or Zone D
and get treatment done in Zone A, then no
type of
copayment is charged. If you
look at the screen here, then everyone has a different
premium. The company has given the highest premium
to Zone D, whereas the lowest
premium is in Zone C. Now let's talk about
discounts, here the company is
providing you credit score discount.  If
your CIBIL score is up to 15,
you
get a discount based on it. The company also
offers a long-term year discount,
meaning if you pay a premium for 2 or 3 years at once, you'll receive a
discount of 10% to 15%. It also
offers an early renewal discount, meaning
if you pay your premium within 30 days of the renewal, you'll receive a
2.5% discount.
So, friends, we've
covered everything about the product. I hope you found it helpful.
We've included the product
brochure and policy wording
in the description link. You
can also browse through them. Friends,
we also offer products from major health insurance,
life insurance, and mutual fund companies and
provide pan-India sales and service.
If you're interested in purchasing any of these products,
you can contact us at the number below.  If you have
any small health related query
then you can ask us in the comment box,
we will try to answer your questions,
if you like the video then like,
share and subscribe, thank you.